# MARTIN ADE

Atlanta, GA 30314 | 404-272-3616 | martin@martinade.com www.linkedin.com/in/martin-ade | www.martinade.com

## **DESIGN DIRECTOR**

## Art director, animator, developer, and design ninja whose playground is the intersection of art and technology

Design leader with 20+ years of experience scrutinizing each project for form and function to design, animate, and code graphics that are beautifully simple and cut through the noise to make an impact on target audiences. Key experience includes branding and launching television networks and developing full-stack web applications. Lead design and programming teams by example, building a culture of innovation and celebrating success; identify, manage, and nurture talent, emphasizing ethics, teamwork, and attention to detail.

**Technical skills:** 

**Design**: After Effects, Photoshop, Illustrator, Ross Xpression, Chyron

**UX/UI**: Adobe XD, Figma, Miro, InVision

Programming: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize, Firebase, Node JS, MySQL, MongoDB

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Turner Broadcasting/WarnerMedia, Atlanta, GA
Turner was acquired by AT&T and renamed WarnerMedia in 2018.

2008 - Present

## Art Director - NBA TV, 2008 - 2017; Design Director - NBA TV, 2017 - Present

Manage technical and aesthetic quality of all project deliverables for 20+ NBA TV properties while maintaining cohesive brand image across promotions, graphics, animations, and web videos. Liaise between design team and various internal departments (social, edit, promotions, production, advertising sales, engineering, and more) and external vendors to create graphics and applications. Supervise and facilitate professional development for a diverse group of 6-10 designers and programmers.

# Accomplishments

- Played a key role in the launch of NBA TV, including establishment of brand identity and overall look and feel for the network and shows. Branded elements included ticker, score bug, animations, show opens, bumps, and interstitials. Within 1 year of rebranding and launch, NBA TV increased subscriber reach to 45 million pay-television homes.
- Spearheaded development of multiple applications to aid in creation of live, statistics-based, informational graphics for live games and studio shows. Implemented Swish (patents pending) on-air graphics population system, which enabled:
  - User friendly, template specific, web based user interface
  - Rapid integration of historical and real-time statistics with design materials for on-air graphics production
  - Remote access to certain designated 'graphics prep stations' from anywhere within the Turner domain
  - Pre-production and saving of graphics to the cloud for upcoming shows
  - Graphic designers to control the look and feel of graphics while on-air operators focused on content and playout.
- Redesigned NBA TV's ticker, score bug and insert packages on multiple occasions to keep the brand fresh.

## **Awards**

- 2015 Promax Bronze Broadcast Design Award: Art Direction & Design: Sports Bumper
- 2013 Promax Gold Broadcast Design Award: Art Direction & Design: Sports Program Bumper
- 2012 Promax Silver Broadcast Design Award: Art Direction & Design: Sports Bumper
- 2012 Promax Bronze Broadcast Design Award: Art Direction & Design: Program-Specific Logo
- 2011 Promax Gold Broadcast Design Award: Art Direction & Design: Sports Program Bumper
- 2011 Promax Gold Broadcast Design Award: Art Direction & Design: Informational Graphics Sports
- 2011 Promax Bronze Broadcast Design Award: Art Direction & Design: Informational Graphics Sports

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

# Fox Sports Net South & SportsSouth, Atlanta, GA

2000 - 2008

Fox Sports Net South rebranded as FSN South in 2004, and acquired a sister network, SportsSouth in 2006.

# Senior Designer - ON-AIR PRESENTATION, FSN SOUTH & SPORTSOUTH, 2006 - 2008

Coordinated all aspects of graphic design for production of regional on-air programming for both networks, including initial design exploration, budget, timeline, pitch and approval, project assignments, design oversight, stakeholder review, delivery to production, and ongoing maintenance of assets. Supervised design team of ~5 people and managed creative department's equipment.

# Accomplishments

- Collaborated with CEO and head of marketing to develop and launch new brand *SportsSouth*, the nation's second-largest regional sports network. Contributed to look and feel of the network and its programming and to development of name, logo, and strategic direction.
- Hired designers that went on to become heads of creative departments at Fox Sports and The Weather Channel.
- Created the animation and branding for Around The South, daily news programs focusing on sports news, stories and highlights across the region.

#### **Awards**

- 2008 Regional Emmy Award: Outstanding Achievement: Graphic Arts
- 2007 Regional Emmy Award: Outstanding Achievement: Graphic Arts
- 2007 Promax Silver Broadcast Design Award: Cable Channels & Networks: Graphic Design
- 2006 Regional Emmy Award: Promotion: Program Single Spot

# Senior Designer - CREATIVE SERVICES / PROMO HUB, FSN SOUTH, 2003 – 2006

Spearheaded design and production of on-air promotions for 3 regional sports networks: FSN South, FSN North, and FSN Arizona. Lead the production of graphics packages for regional sports programs. Handled research, acquisition, configuration, networking, and maintenance of all computers, software, and peripheral hardware used in graphic design. Prepared schedules and disseminated assignments to design team of 3.

## Accomplishments

- Worked closely with the VP of Creative Services, VP of Production, and Executive Producer to maintain the Fox Sports Net "brand" throughout all productions.
- Interfaced with advertising sales team and marketing director to create promotional on-air, off-channel, and point-of-purchase campaigns for client companies such as Pepsi, Dodge, and Nextel.
- Transitioned from creative services department to On-Air Presentations for FSN South & SportSouth in 2006.

#### **Awards**

- 2005 Promax Silver Broadcast Design Award: Cable Channels & Networks: Program Promotion Campaign
- 2004 Regional Emmy Award: Outstanding Collaborative Achievement: Graphic or Electronic Design

## Designer - PRODUCTION, FOX SPORTS NET SOUTH, 2000 - 2003

Oversaw and trained designers in the production of nightly news graphics for The Southern Sports Report and The Arizona Sports Report. Produced graphics packages for regional sports programs (show open animations, interstitial elements, still graphics, templates, etc.).

# Accomplishments

- Trained designers in production of nightly news graphics, using Photoshop and Chyron.
- Earned promotion to senior designer of creative services/promotional hub for 3 networks in 2003.

## **Awards**

- 2003 Regional Emmy Award: Outstanding Achievement: Graphic or Electronic Designer
- 2001 Regional Emmy Award: Outstanding Collaborative Achievement: Graphic or Electronic Design

# **EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT**

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, Atlanta, GA
UX UI Bootcamp Certificate
Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate

ATLANTA COLLEGE OF ART, Atlanta, GA Bachelor of Fine Arts in Digital Art